Welcome back to Apush in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, World War II is over and
looking at America from an economic
standpoint, after World War II, America
goes through massive economic growth and
there is a lot of reasons for this.
Large corporations expand rapidly,
meaning more goods are produced and more
of a consumer economy develops. Also of
note is that the federal government
played a major role in boosting the
economy. Let's go through a few very
important things. The GI Bill provided
all these millions of World War II
veterans with money for college,
housing, and business loans. And the
Interstate Highway Act launched a
massive road building project, which is
the reason there are all of these
highways around the country. So, with
the economy being strong, people wanted
more babies and that's where we see a
massive spike in the birth rate post
World War II known as the baby boom. And
more people in the world means more of a
demand for houses and goods, which is
where we see all of these technologies
on the screen being manufactured in this
time period, which contributed more to
the greater economic boom. So, now we
see a couple of things. The country's
economy is very strong, goods are being
bought and sold at high levels, and now
there are roads all over the place. So,
the result of this will be a lot of
migration. Specifically, millions of
middle-class Americans moved from big
cities to suburbs. The reason for this
is pretty simple. Roads make
transportation way faster, there is
affordable housing with FHA loans in the
GI Bill, and also lots of houses are
being built. And the thing I want to
reference here is mass-produced
neighborhoods full of houses that look
the exact same, which was very common in
this time period known as a Levittown. A
good area where people migrated to was
the Sun Belt. All because of the
recently invented air conditioning,
which made living in this hot region
more plausible. However, despite all of
the economic improvements, you have to
understand that you had to be a very
specific skin color to get access to
these improvements. That's right,
government-backed housing policies often
excluded minorities. This was known as
redlining, by the way, and this would
mean suburban growth was racially
unequal. On the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.